#### ABOUT

Research scientist working at the intersection of machine learning and control theory.

Have 10+ years of experience collaborating with small teams to analyze problems, construct solutions, and effectively communicate the results to stakeholders. Excels at synthesizing and distilling complex concepts/scenarios into easily understandable forms and rapidly acquiring new skills and knowledge.

## Work

Yahoo!, Senior Research Scientist, 12/2023 - Present.

Yahoo!, Research Scientist, 7/2022 – 12/2023.

- Lead of team responsible for control algorithm for bidding in real-time ad auctions.
- Designed and implemented changes leading to a 19% improvement in advertiser ROI.
- Rebuilt institutional knowledge of the algorithm's legacy Java code base.
- Oversaw implementation for ML-based cold-start prediction of the price control signal.

# ACADEMIC HISTORY

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, Assistant Professor, 8/2016 – 8/2021.

Stanford University, Postdoctoral Fellow, 8/2013 - 8/2016.

Institute for Advanced Study, Member, 8/2014 – 8/2015.

# ACADEMIC SUMMARY

Published 10 papers (400+ citations) in geometry and probability in top math journals.

20+ keynote speeches at international conferences (e.g. Germany, France, UK).

20+ research lectures at elite universities (e.g. MIT, Columbia, Berkeley, ETH Zürich).

Taught dozens of math courses at the upper undergraduate and graduate level.

# EDUCATION

University of Chicago, Ph.D., Mathematics, 2013.

National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Research Fellowship

Reed College, B.A., Mathematics, 2007.

Phi Beta Kappa, Barry M. Goldwater Scholarship

#### Contact

Webpage: stromborman.github.io

Email: stromborman@gmail.com

### CITIZENSHIP USA